It's a new day and we are back with a new
video. Hi, hello, and welcome back to our
channel. Tell me something. Do you
prefer to buy your car with cash or a loan?
According to research by an automobile company, 3
out of 5 Indians
prefer to rely on loans to buy cars. Now, there
could be many reasons. Some people do
n't have the funds to buy a car in cash, while
others want to maintain liquidity.
But anyway, the loan seems to be the option here.
Do share your choice in the comments section.
And while we're at it, don't forget to subscribe to our channel
and hit the bell icon for notifications.
Now, we know that
car loans are common in India, but did
you know that
including a car loan in your insurance policy is
necessary? Yes, it is necessary. In today's video,
we will talk about
how to link the loan and insurance, and how to disconnect
them after the loan is cleared.
We will cover the
meaning of
hypotheticals to your insurance policy. The
importance of removing
hypotheticals. So, let's begin.
[Music]
What is Hypothesis? Let's
discuss some basic points of car insurance. Car insurance
is an agreement between the insured and the
insured that covers financial losses
such as accidents, death, and
other damages to the vehicle and its owner.
In India, according to the Motor Vehicles Act, it is
mandatory to have an active car insurance policy. Not having insurance is a punishable
offense. So, if you own a car but do
n't have active car insurance, please
stop everything and get it immediately. Moving
on, Hypothesis
is a method used to pledge assets against a loan.
In this case,
hypotheses
in car insurance, as we discussed earlier, the
majority of India's car-
driving population prefers loans over cash. So,
when you buy a car on a loan,
you don't get full authority over
it. Even though you own it, you still retain the
physical possession of the car. The
car authority is with your lender, i.e., the bank or
NBFC. This agreement is
between you and the bank.  It should
also be a part of your insurance policy.
Wondering why? It's simple. If the bank has
funded your car, then
during an insurance claim, the bank should also get a
share of the compensation. Whenever a
hypothetical claim is made, the settlement amount
goes to both the
hypothetico and the
car owner. For example, if you
receive an insurance claim of ₹5,000,000,
a portion of it goes to the bank, and the remaining
amount is credited to you. This
proportion is
decided based on the hypothecation agreement signed with the bank. Now
you might be wondering how to link your car
insurance policy to the hypothecation. Do
n't worry, we're here to
explain this process step by step.
Documents Required to
Add Hypotheses:
Let's see the documents that are included in your policy's
hypothetical agreements and agreements.
Your personal identification
proof and address proof are required. The
same process applies here. Aadhaar card or
passport serves as identity and address proof.  They're useful,
so keep them handy. You
can also use electricity bills and other utility bills for address proof. RC (RC) is a very
important vehicle document. RC stands for
Registration Certificate and
provides proof that the registered
vehicle is yours. Hypotheses are also
mentioned on RC (Registration Certificate). Bank documents. Now that
you have proof of your identity and car ownership, all that's
needed is
proof of the hypothecation. Here, the agreement between you and the bank is
ready.
To add to the hypothesis,
go to your insurance provider and provide the discussed documents.
Your insurance provider
will verify the authenticity of all the documents.
After verifying the documents, the insurer will
add the hypothesis to your policy. Review your policy
carefully and verify
that the added details are correct. Now, your car
is part of your insurance policy.
Any damage to the vehicle will be covered.
A part of the claim will go to your lender
Moving on Suppose you have
repaid your car loan in a few years, what should you do now? Should you get the
policy removed from the hypothecation
or should you leave it as it is? I will answer that
for you. But before that, I would
like to share an incident. A few days ago, I
went to meet my friend for coffee. He was
waiting at the cafe, looking angry and upset.
I reached on time, so I was wondering
why he reacted like this.
I asked him why his mood
was down and he shared an incident.
Recently, his car had met with an accident
and the car was badly damaged. The repair
charges were very high, so he had made an
insurance claim. Today, he
received the claim amount which was
much less than his expectation. When he
called his agent, he came to know that a
major part of his claim was credited to the bank
which had given him the car loan, but
he had cleared his car loan a month ago,
then why did the claim money go to the bank?
He should have received the full amount.
He had paid his insurance amount.  He fought with the agent
and then it was discovered that he had
n't removed the hypothecation from his policy. The
insurance company claimed the
loan on his car was still active and
transferred the claim amount to the bank. My friend was quite busy with
his office commitments, so he did
n't pay much attention to the details while filing the claim.
Otherwise, he might have found out then. The insurance
agent
asked him to do a lot of things to get a refund, which naturally made him angry.
But can he blame anyone else?
He should have taken
responsibility for not removing the
hypothecation only after clearing the loan.
Now, he is facing the consequences. So, does
this story tell you
why there is a hypothecation?
Keeping that aside, don't you think
it gives a sense of peace of mind to know
that you have cleared all your dues
and there are no financial obligations on your car. It's
a good feeling,
so at least to experience that feeling,
you need
hypothecation clauses for
removing it.  Let's
understand the process of removing the hypothecate
from the claim. The first
document for removing the claim from the claim is the No Objection Certificate (
NOC). Your car loan lender will provide this document,
which states that
all dues have been cleared and you now have
full authority over your vehicle. The
second document required is Form
35, issued by the RTO. After submitting the NOC,
Form 35 is the
hypothetical form for the vehicle. When you
receive the NOC document and file Form 35, the
RTO will have to wait to verify the details
and approve the application. The
RTO takes a few weeks
to process the application. Once approved,
you will receive a new registration
certificate, which states
that you are the sole owner of the vehicle. Take the
NOC and
updated RC to your insurance provider and request them to
remove the hypothecate from the policy.
Some insurance providers
may ask for additional documents, such as a
request letter. You can complete your registration by
providing the relevant documents and making
payments, if required.  Complete the removal application The
insurance company will
verify your application, conduct background checks,
and if everything appears valid,
approve it. You will receive a document containing the
hypothecation. Do
n't forget to check the updated policy carefully to confirm that the
hypothecation has been removed. Car owners
can also use the online facility.
Let's see how
this can be done online. First, go to this website.
Enter your car's registration
number and click on proceed.
Select the basic services option and
enter all your vehicle details. There will be a
button to validate the details.
Click on it. Once validated, you will get the
option to generate an OTP.
Click on it and submit the OTP. Then make the
required payment.
Upload the documents and book an appointment.
Your application will go to the RTO.
When the RTO reviews and approves it, you will
receive an updated RC, which will remove you
from your insurance. Let's move on to the
last part of our video. Everything we have covered now.  Let's
revise what we have learnt so far. Hypothecation of a vehicle
is a process in which you
pledge your vehicle for a loan. It will
remain a part of your insurance policy
until you clear your dues. Any
claim will be divided between you and your insurance company.
After clearing your dues, the first step is to
get the hypothecation title from your documents. So if
you know someone who has a car loan, don't
forget to remind them to
clear the
hypothecation. You might have found it helpful. If you did,
please give us a thumbs up and
share the video with others.
Thanks for watching. See you soon in the next video. Until then,
Happy and Safe
Driving.